Guide to the Ithaca Video Festival media collection, 1977-1983.
Ithaca Video Festival media collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca Video Festival media collection, 1977-1983.
8235
Ithaca Video Festival
2 cubic feet.
Memorex and u-matic format video cassettes
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Videotapes from the screening program of the annual touring video festival.
The Ithaca Video Festival was founded in Ithaca, New York in 1975 under the direction of Philip Mallory Jones.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Videotapes from the screening program of the annual touring video festival.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art.
Subjects:
Video art.; Media art.; Film festivals -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Art festivals -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Due to the fragility and potential degradation of moving image and sound recordings, viewing and listening is limited to items that have been digitized. If an item is in another media format, you may request to have the item digitized for access. Information on ordering access copies may be found on our Reproductions and Permissions page.
CONTAINER LIST
- 3rd Annual Ithaca Video Festival Program #2, 1977; V-8301 (Box 1)
  Contents of tape:
  Eva Maier, "Crystal Palace Tape," 03:45, b/w
  Diane Spodarek, "Milk," 9:00, b/w
  John Orentlicher, "You Send Me," 10:00, b/w
  Fred Simon, "First Memories," 7:00, b/w
  Tomiyo Sasaki, "Dec. 10, 1976," 14:00, b/w
- 3rd Annual Ithaca Video Festival Program #3, 1977; V-8302 (Box 1)
  "Laurie McDonald," Dying Swan," 02:42, b/w
  Dennis Hlynsky, "A New Tape," 02:00, color
  Tobe J. Carey, "Road Kills," 16:00, color
  Bill Viola, "Migrations," 10:00, color
  Kroy DeyRubin, "Curiosity Killed the Cat," 20:00, b/w
- 4th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #1-1, 1978; V-8303 (Box 1)
  Edin Velez, "On the Road to Atitlan," 09:00, b/w
  Vibke Sorensen, "Fibird," 05:40, color
  Karen Simon-Petersen, "Break-Away," 08:00, color
  Tobe Carey, "A Small Self-Portrait," 05:00, b/w
  Steven King, "60, 1/60," 04:00, b/w
  Ann Eugenia Volkes, "Sheridan Square," 20:00, b/w
- 4th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #5-1, 1978; V-8304 (Box 1)
  Bill Viola, "Sweet Light," 10:00, color
  Laurie McDonald, "Minute Waltz," 02:30, color
  Diane Spodarek, "I've Heard That Before," 05:00, color
  Diane Spodarek, "Save the Sixties," 05:00, b/w
  Firzgerald/Sanborn, "Exchange in Three Parts," 30:00, color
  Ernest Gueslla, "Dude Defending a Stare-Case," 03:00, b/w
  Michael Moser, "Movement Study #1," 03:30, color
- 5th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape # A-3, 1979; V-8305 (Box 1)
  John Orentlicher, "Sometime in September," 13:00
  Steve Kolpan, "Untitled Morning Ritual," 09:00
  Reeves/Hilton, "Thousands Watch," 07:00
  Bill and Esti Marpet, "Pyrennes Portrait," 15:42
  Ernest Gusella, "Facial Treatments," 03:55
  Ernest Gusella, "Iris," 03:20
- 5th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape # A-5, 1979; V-8306 (Box 1)
  Peter D'Agostino, "Coming and Going: Paris (Metro)," 05:00
  Mitchell Kriegman, "Always Late," 10:10
  Fitzgerald/Sanborn, "Interpolation," 28:30
- 6th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Series A Tape #2, 1980; V-8307 (Box 1)
  Collectavision, "As A Public Service," 18:00
  Steina, "Bad," 04:00
  Alan Powell and Connie Coleman, "Advance Riding Bowl," 05:00
  Bill Viola, "Chott E Djerid," 28:00
- 6th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Series A Tape #3, 1980; V-8308 (Box 1)
  Doris Chase, "Jazz Dance," 04:00
  Katheryn Kanehiro, "Shutters: Morning I & II," 04:00
  Tom Freebairn and Winston Tong, "Bound Feet," 14:00
  Peer Bode, "Apple(s)," 04:00
  Wright / Craig / MacAdams / Olsen, "California 1," 29:00
- 6th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Series A Tape #4, 1980; V-8309 (Box 1)
  Twin Art, "Instant This - Instant That," 04:00
  Lyn Tiefenbacher and Dave Pentecost, "Bikers' Wedding," 07:00
  William Charette, "Mixed Bag," 08:00
  Laurie McDonald, "Water, Wind and the Record of the Rocks," 10:00
  Ernest Gusella, "The Exquisite Corpse," 08:00
  Pier Marton, "Tapes," 18:00
- 7th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape B #2, 1981; V-8310 (Box 2)
  Adair / Robins, "Live from Lunds," 08:30
  Steina, "Selected Treecuts," 05:35
  Shalom Gorewitz, "Measures of Volatility," 06:00
  John Sturgeon, "2 Aspects," 04:10
  Fitzgerals / Sanborn, "Similar Nature," 08:00
  Gary Hill, "Around & About," 04:45
  Atcheley / Metcalfe, "Crime Time Comic Steel & Flesh," 12:00
- 8th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #1 G, 1982; V-8311 (Box 2)
  Viola, "Ancient of Days," 12:00
  Max Almy, "Deadline," 04:00
  Nori Sato, "Afterimage," 05:00
  William Brown, "Slowly Sounding," 09:00
  Daniel Reeves, "Smothering Dreams," 23:00
- 8th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #2 E, 1982; V-8312 (Box 2)
  Emergence
  Simultaneous
  Somersault
- 8th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #3 G, 1982; V-8313 (Box 2)
  "Meta Mayan"
  "The Vineyard Tape"
  "Split"
- 8th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #4 G, 1982; V-8314 (Box 2)
  "Leaving the 20th Century," 04:30
  Jan Peacock, California Freeze Out," 16:20
  Barbara Buckner, "Millenia (Image Process)," 05:00
  "Indian Circle," 30:00
- 9th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #1, 1983; V-8315 (Box 2)
  "Cage Spot," 00:30
  "Leaving the 20th Century," 10:40
  "Shifts," 10:00
  "Boney," 7:00
  "Zane/Jones Spot," 00:30
  "We Do Not Have Electricity When I Was A Boy," 07:00
  "Tongues," 19:55
- 9th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #2, 1983; V-8316 (Box 2)
  "Bars & Tone," 00:30
  "Ashely Spot," 00:30
  "Beat Plus One," 02:30
  "3rd Step from the Left," 07:00
  "Letters," 05:00
  "Palestine Spot," 00:30
  "60 Flowers, 70 Capsules, 80 Digits," 08:00
  "The Last Hunt," 05:39
  "Forti Spot," 00:30
  "My Black Momma, My White Mom," 27:00
- 9th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #3, 1983; V-8317 (Box 2)
  "Santos Spot," 00:30
  "Unity Through Strength," 06:30
  "OntoGenesis," 06:30
  "Reich Spot," 00:30
  "Spine/Time," 20:00
  "Lucier Spot," 00:30
  "Positively Unsure," 10:30
  "Skin Deep from Outer Space," 05:04
  "Ewart Spot," 00:30
- 9th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #4, 1983; V-8318 (Box 2)
  "Ambassadors of Another Persuassion," 10:00
  "Phillips Spot," 00:30
  "Excerpt," 09:00
  "Anderson Spot," 00:30
  "Plastic Dance," 03:30
  "Wind Falls," 21:00
  "Paik Spot," 00:30
- 9th Annual Ithaca Video Festival Tape #5, 1983; V-8319 (Box 2)
  "Nowhere to Run," 25:00